<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Refactoring on vtemian - blog</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/tags/refactoring/</link><description>Recent content in Refactoring on vtemian - blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vtemian.com/tags/refactoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technical Debt is Cheap</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/technical-debt-is-cheap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/technical-debt-is-cheap/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s hard to write about AI these days without speaking about the elephant in the room. Every single business is pushing AI. We&amp;rsquo;re seeing it everywhere. Google Chrome. Slack. WhatsApp. Even our toothbrushes. A lot of businesses are trying to capitalize on this new tech. And it&amp;rsquo;s raising a negative sentiment.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="toothbrush.png" alt="AI-powered toothbrush">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This negative sentiment is amplified by the &lt;strong>slop&lt;/strong>: shitty images, shitty videos, shitty text polluting websites everywhere. It&amp;rsquo;s not just bad for sentiment. It&amp;rsquo;s bad for the entire internet. Worse, this slop affects current AI research: shitty content trains new models, risking a decline in performance over time. But I think we&amp;rsquo;re just following a normal &lt;strong>hype cycle&lt;/strong>, similar to others we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before. Most recently, blockchain. People get super excited. &amp;ldquo;AGI is here! Jobs are being replaced! We&amp;rsquo;re doomed forever!&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m not that pessimistic.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Healthy Python Codebase</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/healthy-python-codebase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 15:04:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/healthy-python-codebase/</guid><description>&lt;p>The code is a living entity. For the majority of the time, it stays in silence and it&amp;rsquo;s doing its job, without complaining.
But, there are these creatures, humanoid, that from time to time, will change it. Will try to fix it, adapt, or
completely remove parts of it. Those creatures tend to conserve energy and they are using pattern recognition to do so.
They observe patterns and take fast and easy decisions based on those patterns.
Because of that, this code entity needs to be structured and behave in certain patterns.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>