<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on vtemian - blog</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on vtemian - blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 13:06:21 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vtemian.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a serverless hosting platform</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/serverless-hosting-platform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 13:06:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/serverless-hosting-platform/</guid><description>Deploying a 3-tier application (with the presentation layer, business logic, and storage) can get a little tricky these days. Let&amp;rsquo;s say that we have a simple Django application, poll&amp;rsquo;s app from the tutorial. It runs perfect on our local machine, we added a requirements.txt to hold our dependencies. As for the database, we can use SQLite, since we&amp;rsquo;re developing only locally. The purpose of this project is to build a system that will allow us to push on a branch and deploy our changes in a separate environment, giving us a unique URL, to check them.</description></item><item><title>Python Multiple Inheritance</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/multiple-inheritance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 14:03:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/multiple-inheritance/</guid><description>Inheritance, a simple and evil mechanism for re-using code, can get tricky. Traditionally, you may have encountered inheritance when you wanted to extend or override a class&amp;rsquo;s behavior.
class Pet: def walk(self): print(&amp;quot;walk&amp;quot;) def eat(self): print(&amp;quot;talk&amp;quot;) def talk(self): print(&amp;quot;!@#$&amp;quot;) class Dog(Pet): def talk(self): print(&amp;quot;Ham!&amp;quot;) class Cat(Pet): def talk(self): print(&amp;quot;Miau!&amp;quot;) Fairly easy to understand and follow. Dog and Cat share most of Pet&amp;rsquo;s behavior, with some &amp;ldquo;small&amp;rdquo; particularities. Let&amp;rsquo;s say that we want to isolate particular behavior, for better testing purposes.</description></item><item><title>Interviews</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/interviews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 22:02:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/interviews/</guid><description>I’m really nervous, only thinking of them. I had only one or two real interviews and conducted a few. Usually, I’m pretty lucky when it comes to job finding. The companies I like or want to work with contacted me, and it’s really flattering. No interview, just a small discussion, a beer and I’ll start next Monday.
For the past 2.5 years, I’ve started practicing. Practicing maybe it’s too much.</description></item><item><title>2019</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/2019/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 21:36:57 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/2019/</guid><description>So here I am, me, naked, starting a blog.
I must admit, I’m shy and I don’t have any courage. I’ve always been this way. I lack the courage to make decisions, to commit, to trust myself. I’ve always wondered if people will accept me and I’ve tried my best to please and impress people.
This led to a stagnation stage. I was too afraid of trying new things, learning, experimenting, trusting.</description></item></channel></rss>