<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Plan on Vlad Temian - Chief Technology Officer</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/tags/plan/</link><description>Recent content in Plan on Vlad Temian - Chief Technology Officer</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 22:02:12 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vtemian.com/tags/plan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interviews</title><link>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/interviews/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 22:02:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.vtemian.com/post/interviews/</guid><description>&lt;p>I’m really nervous, only thinking of them. I had only one or two real interviews and conducted a few. Usually, I’m pretty lucky when it comes to job finding. The companies I like or want to work with contacted me, and it’s really flattering. No interview, just a small discussion, a beer and I’ll start next Monday.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1535515384173-d74166f26820?ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;amp;ixid=eyJhcHBfaWQiOjEyMDd9&amp;amp;auto=format&amp;amp;fit=crop&amp;amp;w=1350&amp;amp;q=80" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the past 2.5 years, I’ve started practicing. Practicing maybe it’s too much. I bought the books (like everybody does: &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/0984782850-983056789626-Cracking-Coding-Interview/dp/B07F16D3BG/ref=pd_lpo_sbs_14_t_1?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=RD27GF1B4JP3R14XH98M">Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Algorithm-Design-Manual-Steven-Skiena/dp/1849967202/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1546546500&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=Algorithm+Design">The Algorithm Design Manual&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Elements-Programming-Interviews-Questions-Tsung-Hsien/dp/B00C7F0V3W/ref=sr_1_6?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1546546537&amp;amp;sr=8-6&amp;amp;keywords=elements+of+Programming+Interviews">Elements of Programming Interviews&lt;/a>), paid a monthly subscription to leetcode.com, did some problems out there and that was it. I even told all my friends, and they all supported me. But each time I discovered a hard problem or did a mock interview that went bad, I would really feel ashamed and stopped trying. I would procrastinate and find other things to do (like finishing other work-related tasks or start a side-project in a new language etc.).
I wanted to feel safe and comfortable. I felt stupid that I didn’t know how to solve that problem, but I felt smart that I’ve could complete this extra task or did something pointless in a new programming language.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>